<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Shashwat Shekhar &#8211; Shashwat&#039;s InkPot</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/shashwat/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Poetry unscrambled</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 15:06:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Happy DP</title>
		<link>/happy-dp/</link>
					<comments>/happy-dp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shashwat Shekhar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Prose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[durga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ma durga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maa]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The essence of fragrant embersfrom the earthen lamps,inducing a smokey tranceto let my head dance in devotionof your dynamic incarnation. May you possess my soul,to bless my handswhile they sketch your immortal effigy,and hail to the sacred symmetryof your fearful eyes,intimidating away the evil aurawith no trace of it on my canvas. Help me Hey [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The essence of fragrant embers<br>from the earthen lamps,<br>inducing a smokey trance<br>to let my head dance in devotion<br>of your dynamic incarnation.</p>



<p><br>May you possess my soul,<br>to bless my hands<br>while they sketch your immortal effigy,<br>and hail to the sacred symmetry<br>of your fearful eyes,<br>intimidating away the evil aura<br>with no trace of it on my canvas.</p>



<p><br>Help me Hey Maha Gauri,<br>to get lost in deepest slumber,<br>where me, awakened with<br>my pencil and sheet,<br>shall delineate your<br>nine holy figures in the<br>stroke of my devoted faith.</p>



<p><br>Accept my aesthetic piece<br>in the name of pious prayer,<br>as dust of your feet,<br>oh! divine mother of mothers,<br>and guide me thorough my life<br>with your altruistic protection<br>for devotees, as I wake up back<br>into the wicked world<br>Ohe Maa Durga!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/happy-dp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carol of the pearls</title>
		<link>/carol-of-the-pearls/</link>
					<comments>/carol-of-the-pearls/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shashwat Shekhar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 17:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pearls]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hail thou attire of monsoon, Thy rhyme of restless rhapsodic tune, Thy holy flair deluding Ahilya, By carol of the pearls hymning Indra. What sonneteer to pen down thee, What thy ode, what poesy? Here I sing thy unsung praise, In &#8216;manly-tuned&#8217; glorious ways. Homecoming of thine incarnated overcast, Crawling empyrean floor like a toddler [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hail thou attire of monsoon,</p>



<p>Thy rhyme of restless rhapsodic tune,</p>



<p>Thy holy flair deluding Ahilya,</p>



<p>By carol of the pearls hymning Indra.</p>



<p>What sonneteer to pen down thee,</p>



<p>What thy ode, what poesy?</p>



<p>Here I sing thy unsung praise,</p>



<p>In &#8216;manly-tuned&#8217; glorious ways.</p>



<p>Homecoming of thine incarnated overcast,</p>



<p>Crawling empyrean floor like a toddler surpassed,</p>



<p>Screening the age of hoary sky,</p>



<p>Like a young one gladdening grandpa by.</p>



<p>Then, in the sway of tyrannical wind,</p>



<p>Thou slant off the course vertically, grimmed,</p>



<p>Like a youth &#8216;enslaved&#8217; by envious greed,</p>



<p>Sheerly &nbsp;living as &#8216;master&#8217; of breed.</p>



<p>&#8216;Tis not the end, not a frail thou art,</p>



<p>As thunders &amp; flashes happen to start,</p>



<p>What were droplets, art now hail,</p>



<p>No tyranny can hast them sail.</p>



<p>Thy eerie tempest o&#8217;er us, harass,</p>



<p>And tame that wind as hours pass,</p>



<p>Likewise for a man, passes years,</p>



<p>Truns he, bold &amp; potent without fear.</p>



<p>Drizzle thou slowly farewell the skyway, Like a wise old man passes away.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/carol-of-the-pearls/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rainbow seeking colours</title>
		<link>/rainbow-seeking-colours/</link>
					<comments>/rainbow-seeking-colours/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shashwat Shekhar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Article]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homosexual]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lgbtq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[queer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rainbow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seeking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transgender]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The grim of society, endorsed by numerical supremacy of any community has some way or the other, led to progressive suppression of the minors. Here I come to make my words, besmeared with stern history of harassment and discrimination tolerated by LGBTQ community, pierce through the heart of every reader till their funniest topic of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The grim of society, endorsed by numerical supremacy of any community has some way or the other, led to progressive suppression of the minors. Here I come to make my words, besmeared with stern history of harassment and discrimination tolerated by LGBTQ community, pierce through the heart of every reader till their funniest topic of jokes converts to regretful feeling of revolution. Lots and lots of positive light emitted by us are needed to let the ‘spectrum’ scatter its all seven wonderful colours.</p>



<p>The villains of all villains are decorated with utmost prestige by influenceable naive citizens of the world, and specially our countrymen. These unscrupulous, framed gilded as an image of religious leaders have control over the farthest vision of our sight.</p>



<p>Mastered our view so well with the ethics of spirituality from scriptures, that the apex judgement hall of our country, the Supreme Court, failed to make the humane love of LGBTQ community win over the illogical misconceptions of the <em>babas </em>till 2013. Well, not can a man more live</p>



<p>with lies, as for the end only truth suffice. Later the scriptures’ ironical answers to all preachers, “<em>Vikriti Evam Prakriti”, </em>what seems unnatural is also natural, as brought up in the famous book of <em>kamasutra, </em>a full chapter upon homosexuality by Sage Vatsyayna and lastly the depiction of gay sex in Arthashastra by Chanakya were heavy enough to reverse the slope of the scale of justice.</p>



<p>Jubilant tears mixed with giggles of broadest smiles marched across the country, colouring all the streets in rainbow. Like a natural one, it didn’t take more than a handful of happy moments to fade away. Constitutional justice given, social justice denied.</p>



<p>Conservative ‘civilised judges’ with mindset of ‘sex’ as a taboo, couldn’t accept the happiness of a newly discovered minority unlike the supreme and real ones who passed the righteous judgement from the apex court. The lack of literacy and sex education makes the nation pay a lot. Whenever has the dominance of majority influenced the choices of minors, a hundred paths to majoritarianism have invited the</p>



<p>illiterate sections of majority. Unknown to the most prevalent inspirers of local society, homosexuality, bisexualism and transgenderism still fear of their own being. Humans, the self-made kings of biosphere have hit the rock bottom of humanity in uncountable ways, with not accepting the queers, as one. The parents, who had to give birth to a human, always expected their young ones to be a male or a female. Imbecile scientific knowledge they had, didn’t allow them to have just a ‘human baby’.</p>



<p>These imposed thoughts of mankind on man, urge me to repeat so relatable words by Wordsworth, “what man has made of man”.</p>



<p>Hegemony of major sexuality over the minors can never lead to social harmony, but disintegration of the society.</p>



<p>The killing of girl child in womb is replaced by the assassination of character, respect and identity of the minor section of humans for their unique sexuality, which supposedly is unacceptable to the majority. Even dogs of different breeds tend to like each other and get along, unlike faithless us, who marginalised and tabooed transgender humans, before hypocritically preaching</p>



<p>‘hypocrisy and humanity’ on social media tweets. When sea shores cannot control tides, they let the waves taste the beaches, unlike us who’d curse a million for things aren’t in our control. Our sexual orientation possessed by us naturally, is imaged as our own choice, by the social road side judges of the world. Getting rid of fear requires either destruction or negotiation, with the later being a hard choice, it has compelled us to ruin the existence of transgender people. Our bounded sight, so limited to topics of backward caste, women, dark complexion, that the voice of Transgender community has rarely found its way to the issue of discrimination.</p>



<p>The wiser one never regrets his deeds, then how come are transgender suppressed under their own identity of sexuality after every fight for their rights? Do they need to fight back, or the ones they are quarrelling with, need proper education?</p>



<p>Isolating them wasn’t the least we could do, as trolling of the prejudiced has given the funniest laughter to society.</p>



<p>Not satisfied with social torment, we have fallen to the deepest we can for</p>



<p>laughing at their being. A woman with the lap of mother Marry and a man with the boldness of a father, have so far made humorous memories joking about a transgender with all physical and mental characters of parenthood.</p>



<p>Existence of mankind had never been a man’s choice, and neither was the course of our evolution. No one holds the command on a person’s sexuality, but the nature. This fact and education seeks more limelight and sharing than the jokes based on sexuality, for betterment of our vision and society. Human’s mind, falsely nurtured so well with deceitful lies, needs to understand and have the PRIDE for sexuality. Understanding of unstoppable formation of new communities should be endorsed for the sake of neighbourhood, rather ill-treating the one we never understood. Hundreds of pampered lies can be demolished if a single truth prevails with the logical explanation of natural spectaculars.</p>



<p>Respect cannot be imposed but disrespect can be overlooked depending upon the wisdom of perceiver. Contempt in the name of sexuality is discourteous to the mother nature of yours. A fifth grade</p>



<p>student writing essays on ‘unity in diversity’, should not get his brain washed in the ocean of society, disunited over diversity in gender. A place united despite of its diversity, is always one step closer to the utopian society. The exuberant spectrum, tainted by the rustic environment invites the ideas of revolution for the freedom of love and prosperity of majesty. “You never change things by fighting the existing reality.” The permission to love each other given by the supreme court lacked the judgement of society. Although loving is illegal no more, but it’s hard to prosper what society forbids. People read articles on social media, not the constitution of India, therefore must we all unite to write the reforming ideas for recycling of the thoughts of revolution to make the society healthy for every being. Who are crazy enough to think they can change the world the ones to do that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/rainbow-seeking-colours/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Colourful words</title>
		<link>/colourful-words/</link>
					<comments>/colourful-words/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shashwat Shekhar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[color]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colourful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A creak masks the silence of solitude and head, When the poet comforts himself In an olden wooden bed. Wordings laden ladder of Stupor which ends swirling, &#160;He sinks down there, Makes sentences of his feeling. With the brush of a quill He paints his thoughtful mind, With most colourful words On the canvas of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A creak masks the silence</p>



<p>of solitude and head,</p>



<p>When the poet comforts himself</p>



<p>In an olden wooden bed.</p>



<p>Wordings laden ladder of</p>



<p>Stupor which ends swirling,</p>



<p>&nbsp;He sinks down there,</p>



<p>Makes sentences of his feeling.</p>



<p>With the brush of a quill</p>



<p>He paints his thoughtful mind,</p>



<p>With most colourful words</p>



<p>On the canvas of parchment aligned.</p>



<p>&#8220;Oh! Men and women,</p>



<p>Naive critics of the world,</p>



<p>Shall do praise wordless colours</p>



<p>But not colourful words?</p>



<p>Like an alluringly painted canvas,</p>



<p>&nbsp;Are poetic words in a yellow hue,</p>



<p>Standing alone untouched Waiting for literates to walk through.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/colourful-words/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The art &#038; the artist</title>
		<link>/the-art-and-the-artist/</link>
					<comments>/the-art-and-the-artist/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shashwat Shekhar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[and]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shashwat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fishing near the edge of lake with glimmering water, and a goose goofing around in loose muddy shimmering platter. Water lilies laid in the lap of lake, embracing the watery surface, where shall, crickets concert at night echoing up the silent space. Beyond the lake, I could see immortal &#8216;the art&#8217;, I kept wondering a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Fishing near the edge</p>



<p>of lake with glimmering water,</p>



<p>and a goose goofing around</p>



<p>in loose muddy shimmering platter.</p>



<p>Water lilies laid in the lap of lake,</p>



<p>embracing the watery surface,</p>



<p>where shall, crickets concert at night</p>



<p>echoing up the silent space.</p>



<p>Beyond the lake, I could see</p>



<p>immortal &#8216;the art&#8217;, I kept wondering</p>



<p>a blue hill trying to catch the clouds,</p>



<p>as nature, &#8216;the artist&#8217; kept prospering.</p>



<p>The next moment, got seized by a bird,</p>



<p>sprung from the lake, it flew to the sky</p>



<p>along the aisle where hill met the clouds,</p>



<p>I amazed how fake could daydreams be</p>



<p>and unfolded the truths of nature we see.</p>



<p>Branded by gods &amp; bounded by country</p>



<p>that didn&#8217;t &#8216;the artist&#8217; nature do,</p>



<p>leaving &#8216;the art&#8217; immortal no more,</p>



<p>humans &#8216;the masterpiece&#8217; ruined it too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-art-and-the-artist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The butterfly bush</title>
		<link>/the-butterfly-bush/</link>
					<comments>/the-butterfly-bush/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shashwat Shekhar]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 06:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rainbow coloured wings, alike soaked in painter&#8217;s painting palatte little beautiful butterflies on bush of roses beside the lake I paused to name it, &#8216;the butterfly bush&#8217;. Lovely petals with flies around and rainbow wings on rose background both added beauty to each both attracted to beauty of each. Dazzling dews on rosy reds aroused [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Rainbow coloured wings, alike</p>



<p>soaked in painter&#8217;s painting palatte</p>



<p>little beautiful butterflies</p>



<p>on bush of roses beside the lake</p>



<p>I paused to name it, &#8216;the butterfly bush&#8217;.</p>



<p>Lovely petals with flies around</p>



<p>and rainbow wings on rose background</p>



<p>both added beauty to each</p>



<p>both attracted to beauty of each.</p>



<p>Dazzling dews on rosy reds</p>



<p>aroused a fly to fly around</p>



<p>that is what, the work of lust</p>



<p>it flew past down, near the ground.</p>



<p>Got hit in a thorn,</p>



<p>bush was ugly after moment</p>



<p>it flew away so far,</p>



<p>lustful love ain&#8217;t so potent.</p>



<p>Prestigious flower of love</p>



<p>The rose still remains the same</p>



<p>whether we take it as it is</p>



<p>accepted by true lovers and dame,</p>



<p>possess heavenly integrity</p>



<p>has its own beloved fame</p>



<p>it ain&#8217;t no Butterfly Bush but a &#8216;red rose bush&#8217;, it&#8217;s name.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-butterfly-bush/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
